Sweet or savoury?
甜的还是咸的？
Which flavour do you prefer?
你喜欢哪种味道呢？
If like me you have a sweet tooth, you probably can’t resist eating cake, biscuits or chocolate and you‘ll add a few spoonfuls of sugar to your tea or coffee — delicious!
如果像我一样，你爱吃甜食，你可能会无法抗拒吃蛋糕、饼干或巧克力，还会在茶或咖啡里加上几勺糖——太美味了！
But this taste is easily able to ignore warnings that too much of the white stuff is bad for our health.
但是这种味道很容易让我们忽视这样的警告：过多食用这种白色的东西（糖）对我们的健康有害。
Consuming sugar is an addiction - the more we eat, the more we want.
吃糖会上瘾——我们吃得越多，就越想吃。
Today’s processed food, like ready meals, is laced with the stuff and many fizzy drinks contain seven teaspoons of sugar in just one can.
如今的加工食品，比如即食食品，都掺有这种东西（糖），许多碳酸饮料——罐里就含有七茶匙的糖。
In the UK, statistics show that sugar consumption is at its highest level in history and the government is trying to get the food industry to cut the amount of sugar in popular products like chocolate bars by 20% by 2020.
在英国，统计数据显示糖的消费量达到了历史最高水平，政府正试图让食品行业到2020年将巧克力棒等受欢迎产品中的糖含量降低20%。
Of course, sugary food tastes nice, it can help lift our mood, and the glucose in it can give us an energy boost.
当然，含糖食品味道不错，它能帮助改善我们的心情，而且其中的葡萄糖能给我们提供能量。
But there are dangers too: a high-sugar diet is linked to obesity, and being overweight can increase the risk of getting type 2 diabetes.
但也有危险：高糖饮食与肥胖症有关，而且超重会增加患2型糖尿病的风险。
With these warning signs, I have considered changing my diet by replacing sugary snacks with fruit and savoury biscuits — but that‘s boring, I need my sugar fix!
有了这些警告信号，我曾考虑改变我的饮食，用水果和咸味饼干来代替含糖零食——但那很无聊，我需要来点糖！
I’m not alone.
我并不孤单。
BBC journalist Radhika Shanghai, has gone one step further.
英国广播公司记者拉迪卡·尚哈尼更进一步。
Encouraged by some celebrities and nutritionists promoting a ‘zero tolerance‘ approach to sugar, she gave it up altogether, thinking it would make her healthier.
在一些名人和营养学家提倡对糖采取“零容忍”态度的鼓励下，她完全戒掉了糖，认为这样会让她更健康。
Initially she says, “My first fortnight involves mood swings worse than puberty.
起初她说：“我的头两周情绪波动比青春期还厉害。
I have agonising headaches and feel permanently hungover.”
我头痛得厉害，而且一直感觉像是宿醉未醒。”
These symptoms disappeared but she still found food shopping hard as she was stressing about buying the right things.
这些症状后来消失了，但她仍然觉得购买食品很难，因为她为买合适的东西而感到压力很大（还想买糖）。
Her experiment wasn’t a success.
她的实验并不成功。
She eventually sought advice from Susan Jebb, professor of diet and population health at Oxford University who said: “Lots of people enjoy sugar and gain pleasure from it, so one has to find a balance between enjoyment and eating the right amount.”
她最终向牛津大学饮食与人群健康教授苏珊·杰布寻求建议，苏珊·杰布说：“很多人喜欢糖，并从中获得乐趣，所以必须在享受和适量食用之间找到平衡。”
There are health benefits of cutting down sugar such as improving dental care and reducing weight gain, but there‘s no need to be obsessive about it.
减少糖分摄入有很多健康益处，比如改善牙齿护理和减少体重增加，但也没必要对此过于执着。
Eating some sugar as part of a balanced diet is fine and exercising will help burn it off.
在均衡饮食中吃一些糖是可以的，而且锻炼有助于消耗掉这些糖分。
So rather than dealing with your sugar cravings by cutting it out of your diet altogether, why not work on your willpower and learn to say ’no‘ to a second serving of chocolate fudge cheesecake.
所以，与其完全从饮食中戒掉糖来应对对糖的渴望，为什么不锻炼自己的意志力，学会对第二份巧克力乳脂芝士蛋糕说“不”呢？